<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Milking yaks]]></title>
  <link href="http://grota.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://grota.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-15T21:09:05+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://grota.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Giuseppe Rota]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The First of not many. (most likely)]]></title>
    <link href="http://grota.github.com/blog/2012/04/15/the-first-of-not-many-most-likely/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-15T17:05:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://grota.github.com/blog/2012/04/15/the-first-of-not-many-most-likely</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So I finally managed to set up <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a>.</p>

<p>If you don&#8217;t know what Octopress is, suffice it to say that it is a blogging tool that makes it easy to create blog posts in <a href="http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/syntax">Markdown</a> and integrates seamlessly with <a href="http://pages.github.com">Github Pages</a>.<br/>
What I like about it is its nice look, the github integration, but most importantly the fact that it makes it easy to create blog posts simply by opening my editor of choice, <code>vim</code>.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I&#8217;ve always been more of a sponge rather than a contributor (hence the blog name), so I&#8217;m just gonna go ahead and say that I most likely won&#8217;t be able to keep blogging for long.<br/>
I am also trying hard not transform this in a place where I rant endlessly because I already do enough of that in real life and that&#8217;s not an healthy habit.</p>

<p>I just want to use it to study a bunch of cool technologies, like <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">jekyll</a>, <a href="http://sass-lang.org">sass</a>, and the various flavours of markdown available: <a href="https://github.com/rtomayko/rdiscount">rdiscount</a>, <a href="https://github.com/tanoku/redcarpet">redcarpet</a>, <a href="http://kramdown.rubyforge.org/">kramdown</a>, <a href="http://maruku.rubyforge.org/">maruku</a>.<br/>
I can already see in the near future a style change: I like uniform color schemes where the main content has only a slight color difference than the background of the body, but then again I&#8217;m a fan of the <em>green-on-black</em> style of the unix console, so I might be biased.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
